-[mysterious music playing]
-[metal scraping]
[suspenseful music playing]
[young man] They say the moon
wakes the beast inside.
Its light separates
the hunter from the hunted.
Those who run… from those who fight.
-[indistinct chattering]
-[man] Oi.
I'm late. I'm late. Sorry. Excuse me.
[horse neighs]
[gasps, chuckles sheepishly]
Hey!
-Trent!
-[Trent laughs]
-Hey. Come on!
-Wait up!
[Trent laughing]
-[apple thuds]
-[Trent] Oi!
-Thanks for waiting.
-Well, thanks for making us late.
We promised Mum we'd be home before dark.
Whoa. Look at that.
Whoa. A Hunter's Moon.
-[Trent] Yah!
-[horse whinnies]
[adventurous music playing]
[music darkens ominously]
[Wererat snarls]
-[seagulls squawking]
-[pleasant music playing]
[woman chuckles]
Stuffing your face again, Drew?
Oh, ooh. [chuckles]
-Hi, Erin.
-[Erin laughs]
[mockingly] "Hi, Erin."
You dropped this.
[boys grunting]
Thanks.
[man clears throat]
Dream on, Drew.
[chuckles] Don't know what you mean.
[Trent scoffs]
Can we make it to the top of the hill?
The crowd goes wild!
[both laughing]
Oh.
[eerie music plays]
[crows cawing]
[door creaks open]
-Boys! Come and eat!
-[pot clanging loudly]
Move it or lose it.
[Drew grunts]
Oi. Come back here.
[boys panting, laughing]
[boys grunting]
What kept you?
Inside, the pair of you.
[boys grunt, laugh]
[ominous music playing]
[thunder rumbling in distance]
[rain pattering]
[Trent] Well, I'm still going.
I might see Erin.
Anything you want me to give her?
Hunter's Moon.
Not seen one of them since--
Keep your voice down. It's time, Mack.
-We have to talk to Drew.
-I don't know, Tilly.
We should have told him already.
We took an oath.
If he finds out the truth,
it changes everything.
I'll do it. Tonight.
After dinner.
[thunder crashing]
[Drew sighs]
[slurping]
It's like he's never been fed.
[Tilly chuckles]
[Drew groans]
Not hungry, lad?
-Feels like my bones are burning.
-Oh, you won't be needing this, then.
Hey! [grunts in pain]
-Drew.
-[Drew groaning]
[Drew pants in distress, cries out]
[Mack gasps]
Trent. Help your dad fetch the flock
before the storm hits.
-Hang on. I-- I did it yester--
-Come on. You heard her.
[somber string music playing]
[Mack grunts]
[rain pouring]
[Wererat growls]
[thunder rumbling]
[mystical music plays eerily]
[Drew grunting in distress]
Drew, listen to me.
You have to leave. Tonight.
-What are you talking about?
-[Tilly] You can't stay.
You're not like the rest of us.
What? Yes, I am.
I thought we'd have more time.
Whatever happens, just remember,
you were always my boy.
You're not making any sense.
Take this with you.
[ominous music playing]
[Tilly gasps]
[door slams shut]
Come away from the window.
Drew, move!
[thunder rumbling]
[door crashes]
[floorboards creaking]
[Tilly whimpers]
[gasps]
[creaking stops]
Shh!
[wood thumping]
[thunder crashes]
-[glass shattering]
-[suspenseful music playing]
[Drew groaning]
[Wererat snarling]
What is that?
Stay back, Mum!
[Tilly] Drew! No!
[Wererat snarling]
Get away from my boy!
-[Tilly screams]
-What was that?
Tilly.
Come on!
-[Wererat snarling]
-[Tilly grunting]
-[dagger clatters]
-Mum!
[gasps weakly] You can't have him.
-[thunder crashes]
-[Wererat growls]
Mum!
[eerie music playing]
-[music intensifies]
-[Drew groaning]
[electricity crackling]
[Drew growls]
[Drew yells]
[Wererat snarls]
-Come on!
-Mum!
[Mack] What's going on in there? Tilly!
Tilly, come here, my love!
Tilly, open the door!
[Drew] Mum!
[Tilly whimpering softly]
Go now. Go to Brackenholme.
Brackenholme?
I'm not leaving you.
Find Duke Bergan.
Say it.
[sniffles] "Find Duke Bergan."
He will help you. He'll show you the way.
-What do you mean?
-You're the…
-[banging on door]
Mum!
[door crashes open]
[thunder crashes]
Drew, what have you done?
Mum? You killed her!
-Get back, Trent. Stay away from him!
-Dad?
I should never have left her with you.
Trent.
Get back!
-No!
-[Mack grunts]
[Mack panting]
Tilly.
Dad.
Dad!
Boy, throw me the poker.
The silver one, quickly! Here!
[Drew cries out]
[horn bellows]
[Drew panting]
-[Mack] Where is he?
-[villager] This way!
-[thunder crashes]
-[Mack] This way!
[villagers clamoring]
That way. He's over there!
-Quick! He's headed for the Dyrewood!
-Wait! Why are you after Drew?
He killed Tilly.
-What?
-It's true.
Bring the dogs!
I can get him, Dad. Leave him to me.
[Drew panting]
[groans]
[shouts]
[eerie music plays]
[panting]
[Trent] Draw your sword.
Trent, I'm your brother.
Not anymore!
[Trent yells]
[suspenseful music playing]
[blade slicing, clanging]
-[Trent yells]
-[Drew grunting]
-[Trent gasping]
-[axe cracks]
-[Drew gasps]
-[villagers yelling]
Erin.
He's down there!
This way!
[Mack yells]
What's it gonna be, Drew?
[Drew] Hunter or hunted?
Fight or flight?
[suspenseful music playing]
[ethereal music plays]
[Drew grunting]
[villagers shouting]
[Mack sighs]
[eerie music playing]
[eerie night chirping]
[running footsteps approaching]
[spiders chittering]
[Drew panting]
[eerie music playing]
[panting]
[gasps] What?
[man] This is Wyldermen country.
So be on your guard.
Right. Ready for your final test?
Yes, Master.
Go find a place to make camp,
and choose wisely.
Fend for yourself,
and I'll return at first light.
-Take the map in case.
-But--
I know, I know. One day you won't need it.
But for now, keep it close.
Whatever happens,
you can get back to Brackenholme.
[whispers] Brackenholme?
Whitley. You've studied for this test?
[Whitley] Hm.
Then, by morning,
you'll be a fully-fledged scout.
And if that doesn't impress my father…
[man chuckles]
[tense playing]
[twig snaps]
-[trap clamps]
-[Drew screams, moans]
[grunting]
Hm. My snare works, then.
-You don't look like a Wylderman.
-That's because I'm not.
[grunts]
So, you're a thief,
trying to steal my map.
[Drew] Please, just cut me down.
And why would I help
a thief with a stolen sword?
My name's Drew. Drew Ferran.
I need to get to Brackenholme.
My mum said to find a man called Bergan?
Duke Bergan is never going to meet
with a lowlife like you.
[mockingly] Whatever your mother says.
[Drew gasps]
[scoffs] I haven't got time for this.
[Drew cries out]
[moaning]
[horse neighs]
Look…
At least tell me who this Bergan is.
He's only the Duke of Brackenholme.
And if you'd ever seen him take the shape
of the Great Bear in battle,
you wouldn't need to ask.
He's a Werelord?
The bravest.
The last one to stand up for the people.
Against who?
-The Lions?
-Enough questions!
-But--
-I'm passing this test.
So stay out of my way.
[horse whinnies]
[suspenseful music playing]
-[man shouts]
-[gasps]
[man shouting]
-[Whitley grunts]
-[horse whinnies, snorts]
-[man] No!
-Master Hogan?
[horse whinnies]
[Hogan] No!
-Hello?
-Ugh.
[Drew clears throat]
Look… What about, if I help you,
you tell me what I need to know.
-Whoa!
-[skull crunches]
-[Drew gasps]
-Oh no.
What is it?
It looks like some kind of… [yells]
[both whimper]
[eerie music playing]
[Whitley gasps]
[creature snarls]
Shh.
[Hogan grunts, pants]
Wyldermen!
[suspenseful music playing]
Master Hogan!
Run, child!
I'm not leaving you!
[Wyldermen growl]
[Wyldermen screech]
[horse neighing]
Chancer!
[grunts]
[cries out]
[groans]
-[screams]
-[Wylderman screeches]
The map!
No!
[Wylderman snarls, screeches]
[Chancer whinnies]
[shouting]
[Drew groans]
[Wylderman yells]
-[screeches]
-[body thuds]
[Whitley panting]
Why did they attack?
Whatever this place is,
it's important to them.
We need to get out of here.
[gasping for breath] Can't… breathe.
[groans]
Poisoned arrow.
-You need to get him to Brackenholme?
-The map's gone.
But he knows the way.
And he's in no state to guide us.
-We need to fix him.
-With what?
We need yellowstem. I know where to look.
Well, don't just sit there. Come on!
[both grunt]
[ominous music playing]
[Wererat growls, sniffs]
[snarling]
[water lapping gently]
[bird hooting in distance]
[Trent crying softly]
[footsteps approaching]
[Mack sighs]
I don't understand.
She loved him.
-He was her favorite.
-He was never like us.
All this time… Is he even my brother?
[Mack] I'm sorry, son.
It's just you and me now.
[footsteps marching]
[suspenseful music playing]
Lion Troopers.
Erin, get inside.
-We can't stay here. Let's go.
-I'm not going like nothing's happened.
Someone needs to make Drew pay.
Trent, wait.
They're the law.
I'm telling them what he did.
[sighs heavily]
Trent, watch what you say to them!
-Back up, boy.
-You're looking for Drew Ferran.
I can help you.
I'm his brother.
Was his brother.
Let's hear what he has to say.
Trent, no.
[trooper] Boy's got friends in Motley.
Turn it upside down!
Find him. Whatever it takes!
[Hogan moans]
[gasps] Up there!
[eerie music playing]
[Hogan groaning]
[grunts] I've got him.
It's all right, Master. I'm here.
He's getting worse.
You stay with him.
Let me get the yellowstem.
[scoffs] Whatever.
Just don't come back without it.
-And you'll get me to Brackenholme?
-Yeah, if he lives.
If he doesn't, we all die here.
Well, what are you waiting for? Go!
[Drew grunting]
[grunting continues]
[exhales]
Yellowstem.
-Mind the moss!
-[Drew grunts]
That is not moss.
-[footsteps squelching]
-[Drew gasps]
[ominous creaking]
[Drew gasps]
[creature growls menacingly]
[Drew gasps, wails]
Whoa!
I can't move!
Drew!
[Drew grunts]
He can't be.
I'll be back, Master. I promise.
-Hold on. I'm coming!
-[Drew groaning]
[grunting]
[Whitley grunts]
[spider screeches]
[screeching cry]
[Whitley grunting]
[screams]
[spider screeches]
[growls]
[Drew grunting]
[spider growls, screeches]
[spider thuds]
[Drew panting]
[both grunting]
-Easy, easy.
-[Hogan moans]
Will he live?
We've bought him some time.
If his fever breaks.
-Thank you.
-Don't look at me.
-Don't you know what you are?
-Some kind of freak?
You're a Werelord.
-[mystical music plays]
-It takes one to know one.
[gasps] You're a…
I'm a Bearlord.
So what does that make me?
Well, you must come from
one of Lyssia's seven great houses.
You don't have any idea?
My mum, she knew, I think.
She didn't get a chance to tell me.
Why do you need to see
Duke Bergan so badly?
She made me promise.
It was the last thing she said to me.
I'm sorry.
[Drew sniffles]
Well, whatever you are,
I don't believe you're with the Lions,
or you'd have left us to the Wyldermen.
-Why would the Lions want you dead?
-Because King Leopold is a tyrant.
He's put down every rebel
since he stole the crown.
Stole it?
-From the Wolf.
-That's not right.
It is, Drew.
[mysterious music playing]
[Whitley] Each realm had its own Werelord.
[bear growling]
[Whitley] Sharks…
and Stags.
Rats and Bears.
Like Duke Bergan.
And all the Werelords
pledged allegiance to the noble Wolves
until the Lions came and destroyed them.
The Wolves held Lyssia together
for centuries.
[lion growls]
[Whitley] Now the Lions have
all Seven Realms by the throat.
Everybody lost someone
when the Lions came.
[distant screaming]
[Whitley] Parent, neighbor,
sister.
-[dark music playing]
-[lion growling]
[Whitley] What the world would give
for the return of a Wolf.
But I thought the Wolf was the tyrant.
That's what the Lions want you to believe.
Join us.
We need all the Werelords we can recruit.
Why me?
-A rebellion has to start somewhere.
-Rebellion?
Duke Bergan will tell you what you are.
[sighs] With any luck,
it might spur the old Bear into action.
[Hogan cries out] Wyldermen.
[groaning]
Shh. Master. You're safe.
[Hogan gasping] An Orb Spider.
We dealt with it.
Idiots.
The Wyldermen worship Orb Spiders.
-What does he mean?
-Oh no.
The clearing.
-Those bones.
-They were laid out like a web.
You disturbed their shrine.
And now you've killed one of their gods.
-[distant screeching]
-[ominous music playing]
[screeching grows closer]
[rhythmic beating on trees]
We need to move.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Hogan] This way!
The Dymling Road!
-[Hogan grunts]
-[Chancer neighs]
[Whitley] There it is!
We made it! Come on. Let's keep moving.
-[Chancer whinnies]
-[Whitley] Come on, Chancer!
-What's gotten into you?
-Something's wrong.
They're hunting us. They're right behind.
That's what they wanted us to think.
They're herding us. It's a trap!
-[terrifying music playing]
-[branches crackling]
[Whitely shouts]
Whitley!
[Drew grunts, yells]
[struggling]
-[snarls]
-You.
[Whitley grunting]
[horn bellows]
-[Hogan] Get back!
-[Whitley gasps]
[snarling]
[Chancer whinnies]
[Whitley grunts]
Chancer, come on!
Drew, where are you?!
[yells]
Go to Brackenholme. Find Duke Bergan.
[Drew yelling]
[Wererat growling]
[Wyldermen growling menacingly]
[snarls]
[thunderous growling]
[dramatic music playing]
[roars]
[Drew panting]
[Drew grunts]
[bear growling]
Wake the healers at the White Oak.
Take Hogan straight to them.
[Whitley] Father! [laughs]
This is your father?
You are not going to believe
what I have brought home with me.
Other than a pack of Wyldermen?
And a boy?
Oh, he's more than that. He's a Werelord.
A new one.
-Get him up.
-[Drew grunts]
My, um…
My mum sent me.
She said you'd help me. Help me to--
I don't have time for this.
Ah, ah!
We don't want you here!
[Drew grunts]
Please! Just hear me out!
Leave! Now!
But… But, Father!
No, Whitley.
Wait…
But we need him.
To fight back against the Lions.
[Duke Bergan] Keep your voice down.
The Lions are already here.
Whitley!
[trooper 1] On your way.
[ethereal music playing]
[Drew] What beast am I?
Do I run for my life…
or fight for it?
Only the Wolves
could have made a stand against the Lions,
and they're gone.
You're not listening!
[trooper 2] Huh? What's going on?
-[Whitley] Father!
-[trooper 2] No.
[troopers shouting, grunting]
[Whitley panting]
[troopers wailing]
Drew.
Drew?!
[Drew growls]
Drew Ferran.
You're a… You're a Wolf.
A Wolf?
The Wolf.
[Drew breathing heavily]
[Duke Bergan] What's going on? Whitley!
Get back!
[Drew groaning]
-[Whitley gasps] Drew!
-Whitley? [crying out]
Where are you taking him? Father!
Stop! Please!
Whitley!
Drew!
[music fades]
[closing theme music playing]